## Benjamin Paulsen

### Developer & Designer

Website bjpaulsen.github.io Email bjpaulse@ucsc.edu Phone (831) 428-3680

#### **SKILLS**

Open. Respectful of different ways of thinking, open to feedback, and communicative.

Skilled. Developed in C, C++, Java, Python, MIPS Assembly, Javascript, and HTML/CSS.

Versatile. Experienced with game design, web design, graphic design, visual art, UNIX, Git.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Tech4Good Lab** - Undergraduate Research Fellow, Frontend Developer JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

 Created next-generation learning platforms that explore new research into social computing and computational media.

#### **UC Santa Cruz, Learning Support Services** - Computer Science Tutor

SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2019

- Taught groups of university students how to program, debug, and problem-solve.
- Collaborated to better accommodate students with disabilities and learning differences.

#### **Game Development Projects** - Designer, Programmer, Artist

DECEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Designed and created original, playable video games from scratch. (see portfolio)
- Developed practical experience in physics simulation, Java, Javascript, OOP, C, C++.

#### Winner at HackACM 2019 - Hackathon Beginner Category

**APRIL 2019** 

• Built a loop pedal musical performance tool in Java with a small team in under 12 hours.

#### Santa Cruz Parks And Recreation, Scotts Valley Library - MAKE Lab Intern

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Ran popular technology showcase events at the Scotts Valley Library.
- Taught children, teens, adults, and seniors about using computers, tools and tech.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of California, Santa Cruz** - *Undergraduate in Computer Science: Game Design* FALL 2018 - PRESENT

# Benjamin Paulsen

### Developer & Designer

Website bjpaulsen.github.io Email bjpaulse@ucsc.edu Phone (831) 428-3680

#### REFERENCES

Timothy Nguyen - Team Lead, Tech4Good Lab

Tech4Good Fellow tim.nguyen.cs@gmail.com

**Jaqueline Morales** - Supervisor, UCSC Learning Support Services

Assistant Director of Tutoring jmoral11@ucsc.edu (831)-459-3462

**Jennifer Hooker** - Supervisor, Scotts Valley Library

Librarian II hookerj@santacruzpl.org (831) 427-7706 ext.7647